Owen Campbell

Email Website Location

Mobile Phone +44 (0)7799 111652 owen.campbell@tanti.org.uk owencampbell.me.uk Helsby, Cheshire UK

Profile

I am a Chartered Engineer and I consult in software development and implementation projects.

Typically, I'll have responsibility for the technical strategy of a project and I'll lead a team of client and contract staff to deliver that strategy.

I have an interest in introducing agile techniques for the first time to organisations and projects that may not have used them previously and I particularly enjoy 'rescue' assignments for projects that are perhaps not proceeding as desired.

I have a thorough understanding of technology and business processes and practical experience of many diverse operational environments.

I have the soft skills to operate effectively in the board room, IT and Finance departments and with end users, developers, system administrators and suppliers.

I have a proven track record of delivering practical, successful solutions and previous clients willing to support that claim.

Achievements

Some of the more notable projects undertaken in recent years include:

- Fixed Assets Implementation for a UK Housing Group Design and implementation of component accounting for a UK Housing Group with a portfolio of over 25 000 properties
- New Finance System Implementation for a Multi-National UK PLC Design and implementation of a new finance system for a UK PLC with over 100 multi-national subsidiaries and including full data migration of all historical transactions
- New Finance System Implementation for a National UK Retail Company Design and implementation of external interfaces, reporting templates, and historical data-load for a new finance system implementation. Successful go-live within 6 month deadline.
- Finance System Roll Out to an Overseas Subsidiary of a UK Engineering Company Data-loading, interface design, configuration and testing for a fast-track, high-profile implementation of a new Canadian acquisition within a live UK system. (150 new users within a 1200 user system).
- System Integration for a UK Engineering Company Successful integration of a document management and project accounting system to provide tendering and specification functionality (1000 user system)
- Roll Out of a Standardised Configuration to all Subsidiaries of a UK Financial PLC Design and implementation of a standardised configuration across a multi-country, multi-company operation (approx. 100 subsidiary companies)
- Implementation of Project Based Accounting for a UK Software PLC Design and implementation of the addition of project accounting to an existing multi-country operational system
- Bespoke Interface Design for a UK Higher Education Establishment Design and implementation of an interface between a student record and finance system

Owen Campbell

Mobile Phone Email Website Location

+44 (0)7799 111652 owen.campbell@tanti.org.uk owencampbell.me.uk Helsby, Cheshire UK

Knowledge, Experience and Skills

Technology Python, Django, AngularJS,

Oracle & PL/SQL, MS SQL Server & T-SQL, Postgresql

Ruby, Rails, Java, C#, Scala

Linux & Bash, Windows & Powershell

Sectors Professional Services, Retail, Finance, Higher Education, NHS Trusts, National and

Local Government, Charities

Project Types System Selection, Development, Implementation, Upgrading, Interfacing

Employment History

2001 - Current Owner and Director, Empiria Ltd

In March 2001, along with two colleagues, I left Eutech to form my own consulting

company, Empiria Ltd.

1998 – 2001 **Business System Manager**, Eutech Ltd

In 1998, ICI decided to sell Eutech and I became the lead engineer on a project to implement an integrated financials, logistics, project accounting and HR system. I then became the manager of that system and led its maintenance, development

and support.

1994 – 1998 **Technology Project Manager**, Eutech Ltd

Eutech was a wholly owned subsidiary of ICI PLC which provided engineering con-

sultancy services to the process industries.

I joined at its inception in a role providing technical leadership of collaborative R&D projects between ICI PLC and other EU organisations. I particularly specialised in

the innovative design and use of relational databases.

1990 – 1994 **Project Engineer**, ICI PLC

I joined ICI as a graduate engineer and worked on a variety of engineering projects

for ICI businesses in the UK.

Education and Qualifications

1995 **CEng MIET** Chartered Engineer, Member of the Institution of Engineering Technology (www.theiet.org Formerly the Institution of Electrical Engineering)

1990 **BEng (Hons)** Engineering Science and Technology (University of Loughborough)

Interests and Hobbies

I am a voluntary senior manager for the UK Scout Association (District Commissioner for the Mersey Weaver Scout District: www.merseyweaverscouts.org.uk).

The role involves overall responsibility for the delivery of Scouting to the District's 1250 young people and line management of its 250 adult volunteers.

I'm also a core team member of the Axelrod-Python project (https://github.com/Axelrod-Python/Axelrod).